<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ens on A Hugo website</title>
    <link>/en/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ens on A Hugo website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/en/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Minimal App with R markdown</title>
      <link>/2023/02/10/minimal-app-with-r-markdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2023/02/10/minimal-app-with-r-markdown/</guid>
      <description>some feedback from yihui’s talk on youtube.
I tried the code he present on the video. I can see it did minimized the file size without affecting the feeling of the web browsers.
One important change is to use the output: html_format to replace the output: html_document on the YAML metadata. This has been built into a GUI if you used the R studio by creating a new rmarkdown specifying the html output.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>加拿大的元宵节</title>
      <link>/2023/02/07/%E6%97%A5%E5%B8%B8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2023/02/07/%E6%97%A5%E5%B8%B8/</guid>
      <description>2023 元宵节。11点左右我起来练了一会儿瑜伽，
练完, 出门去教会了。牧师讲道的时候，我记得其中一个很有趣的栗子：
“牧师一家在吃饭的是时候遇到一个十分粗鲁的服务员。付小费的时候，牧师觉得不应该给小费，牧师女儿觉得不仅要给还要多给一些。牧师很不理解，女儿解释：如果我们不给小费，他不会感到意外，如果我们给多小费，他就有可能改变。”
可接受失去范围内给与而不计较得失。</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SAS ADV into R</title>
      <link>/2023/01/03/sas/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2023/01/03/sas/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 10
Compare the symput and symputx difference, symput with x will give automatically removes leading zero and trailing blanks from the arguments. symget ()
SYMPUT routine create or update macro variables during DATA step execution.
performs automatic numeric to character conversion on any numeric value that you attempt to assign to a macro variable. SYMGET obtain the value of a macro variable during the execution of a DATA step, a PROC SQL step, or an SCL program.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>review my statistics</title>
      <link>/2022/06/22/i-am-crazy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2022/06/22/i-am-crazy/</guid>
      <description>Multicollinearity what is multi-col-linearity
the problem of having multi-col-linearity
what cause the multi-col-linearity
using the VIF
Solve the multicollinearity
muticollinearity is observation on the data when two or more variables are highly correlated with each other.
makes the interpretation of the variable to the target variable hard. For example, one unit of increase on x1 will case xxx increase/decrease on target variable when multicollearity happens. unremovable variable or the vairbales are important in predict</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploratory Data Analyst (SQL)</title>
      <link>/2022/06/21/exploratory-data-analyst-sql/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2022/06/21/exploratory-data-analyst-sql/</guid>
      <description>Exploratory Data Analyst applies to the following cases: vague targets or problems to the large data set
large data set needs cleaning
Benefit of the exploratory data analyst: help find the inner pattern or relationship through the data
help to categorize the variables for the further analysis. (missing, outlier etc.)
Three type of data Numeric data We would like to know the min and max, average, variance and correlation and percentile to this type of data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meta Analysis</title>
      <link>/2021/07/09/meta-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2021/07/09/meta-analysis/</guid>
      <description>ref
NOTE: most words are from the ref above, and it is a mini summary from my own perspective. Since I am truly not able to find the better word to describe.
Meta Analysis is a method used the data results from individual studies. Studies are coming from computerized Literature Search of a database such as PudMed etc. The auto search are based on the participants, interventions, comparison and study designs indicated in the contrasts of the scientific papers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Git help</title>
      <link>/2021/05/03/githelp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2021/05/03/githelp/</guid>
      <description>Git is a free and open source distributed version control system.
working directory.
staging area(index). git repository. three different objects generate from git cmd and describe in Hash:
blob: only save the content of the file instead the file name. tree: the file name. commit: the first commit also called root commit. git basic git init: generate a file called /.git/ used ls -a to see all the hided files.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cv&#43;resume</title>
      <link>/2021/04/22/resume/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2021/04/22/resume/</guid>
      <description>Looking for position: Data Analyst
Dear Manager
I am writing to express my keen interest in Data Analyst position in the [Company Name].
I graduated from the Bio-statistics master program in the year 2019 and started to work in TD bank as Data Support Analysis. My passion and motivation came from assisting shareholder make decision from data-driven outcomes and tutoring in subject: elementary programming, math, elementary statitiscs. I have both experience in tutoring both students in lower level university and elementary school.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SQL</title>
      <link>/2021/03/18/sql/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2021/03/18/sql/</guid>
      <description>DEFINATION OF RELATION TABLES HOW TO CHANGE THE ENTITY TO A SCHEMAS CASE WHEN SUBQUERY COMMON TABLE EXPRESS (cte) WINDOW FUN ROLLUP and CUBE TABLESAMPLE UNPIVOT:ROW TO COLUMN PIVOT:COLUME TO ROW Some information contains from Datacamp, you can use my refer to get started and learn new technique together.
DEFINATION OF RELATION TABLES entity: (table) the object store the information
attribute: column in a table to describe the part of the information</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Plain Markdown Post</title>
      <link>/2016/12/30/a-plain-markdown-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2016 21:49:57 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/12/30/a-plain-markdown-post/</guid>
      <description>This is a post written in plain Markdown (*.md) instead of R Markdown (*.Rmd). The major differences are:
You cannot run any R code in a plain Markdown document, whereas in an R Markdown document, you can embed R code chunks (```{r}); A plain Markdown post is rendered through Blackfriday, and an R Markdown document is compiled by rmarkdown and Pandoc. There are many differences in syntax between Blackfriday&amp;rsquo;s Markdown and Pandoc&amp;rsquo;s Markdown.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
