<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>A Hugo website</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on A Hugo website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>论怎么克服code的畏难情绪</title>
      <link>/2021/06/02/code/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2021/06/02/code/</guid>
      <description>好久一阵没有更新我的blog了，每次看完谢大的blog，都有被打鸡血的感觉，更新博客更新博客。然后每次都是算了，反正没人看， 这次的写这个博客主要是好久因为畏难，不想练习写code， 然后加上在无线负能量，加之自闭的情绪下，就算是给自己的一通打起好嘞（我自己看）。
嗯，是这个样子的，R 和 python 叫啥，计算机语言， 啥是语言，就是方便交流用的工具。这个现在常用的两个语言， 建立在英语的语法上开发出来的，这也是为啥， 现在我们在刷小红书的时候，看到很多标题： 说转计算机不要数学好，文科生转码农。我觉得是十分的合理的。 毕竟是语言吗，只要因为小学毕业都可以去做码农。那我们从小是怎么学习语言的呢？ 听说读写， 听是默写，说是读书，读是阅读，写是写作。那练习编程就是 听，多听点音乐，说，就是偶尔唱唱歌尤其实在想不出来可以自言自语，或者骂人，阅读这个比较重要了，就是多看人家写的code， 最后就是最重要的是多写。 任何语言，只要不用，就不会擅长，毕竟这个是一个技术，很多时候 不是考验智商，因为现在网络的发达，怎么借助比你厉害的人的力量的能力也是尤其重要的。 但是话又说回来了，自己懂英语和老外交流 比用个电子翻译机跟舒服不是吗，所以我的意思就是，你别怕，反正都能写，咱们尽量自己写，实在不行抄抄理解一下，尊重版权，就无伤大雅。 总而言之，你怕啥，不会写，你会抄吗。记得以前我们上学的时候，有些级别，学霸开源，学渣跟着抄抄，学精是边抄边想为啥这个作业是这样写的。
最后一件事，我在思考谢大的话，统计是先想为啥在想怎么做，编程是先去实现在想为啥，所以我对于想学编程但是却因为畏“难”影响的朋友说（其实就是我自己） 先复制粘贴，跑起来吧。。。。。。。。。跑完了，在想咦我为啥跑，怎么跑更快。好嘞， 今天就到这了思密达！！！</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Git help</title>
      <link>/2021/05/03/githelp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2021/05/03/githelp/</guid>
      <description>Git is a free and open source distributed version control system.
working directory.
staging area(index).git repository.three different objects generate from git cmd and describe in Hash:
blob: only save the content of the file instead the file name.tree: the file name.commit: the first commit also called root commit.git basicgit init: generate a file called /.git/ used ls -a to see all the hided files.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cv&#43;resume</title>
      <link>/2021/04/22/resume/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2021/04/22/resume/</guid>
      <description>Site: The Bishop Strachan SchoolPosition: Data Analyst
Dear Manager
I am writing to express my keen interest in Data Analyst position in the Bishop Strachan School.
I graduated from the Bio-statistics master program in the year 2019 and started to work in TD bank as Data Support Analysis. My passion and motivation came from assisting shareholder make decision from data-driven outcomes and tutoring in subject: elementary programming, math, elementary statitiscs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>皮肤管理</title>
      <link>/2021/04/21/%E6%8A%A4%E8%82%A4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2021/04/21/%E6%8A%A4%E8%82%A4/</guid>
      <description>年纪大了皮肤不如以前抗氧能力强了,学习护肤.
步骤   早上：每天
 洁面（如果感觉太干可以省略） 微微湿润的时候，眼部，两滴玻尿酸在面霜里面 涂抹防晒    晚上： 每天
 洁面 脸微微湿润的时候，视黄醇 1-3 次每周在面霜 加上凡士林， 每周1-2 次    NOTE
洗脸20 s to 1 min, 指尖按摩确保干净, 水温 36-40 °
Lactic acid 乳酸+玻尿酸 有两种,一个是5%一个是10%, 可以自己选择
产品选择:   洗面奶
 Cerave    面霜
 Elizabeth Arden    玻尿酸(hyaluronic acid)
 the inky list    水杨酸（Salicylic Acid): 只要是收缩毛孔，和一些斑纹吗，建议晚上使用，但是不要和Retinol（视黄醇）
 Bobbi Brown: + 蔷薇果 (Rose hip)，摩洛哥坚果油，    防晒霜（sun cream)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Experimental Design </title>
      <link>/2021/03/26/experimental-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2021/03/26/experimental-design/</guid>
      <description>Some concepts and examples in Experimental Design
experimental study: a study subject is assigned the treatmentobservational study: a study with subject is observed or measuredexperimental unit: in an experimental study, basic entity can be assigned is called experimental unit. The experimental unit is people, called subject. At observational and experimental study, subjects are called participants.
Experimental DesignA good experimental design will need:1. treatments are random assigned to the experimental unit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Missing Data</title>
      <link>/2021/03/24/missing-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2021/03/24/missing-data/</guid>
      <description>Missing dataWhat types of missing data?Missing completely at randomMissing at randomMissing not at randomWhat technique to handle missing data?Listwise or case deletion：assumption：sample size are large
con: simple implementpro: loss given informationPairwise deletion?assumption： not missing here and there,con：compare with the listwise, the lost information reducedpro：cause inaccurate stand error as the knowingMean substitutionn?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog Down</title>
      <link>/2021/03/21/blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2021/03/21/blog/</guid>
      <description>get start:hugo go:configContentFront matterTemplates_default/list.html:terms.htmlPartials/.stores the templates reused in other html pages by the {{ partial }} function.footer.htmlCustom layoutsStatic filesLastlyAddin ….get start:here we go. already started
hugo go:a tool we we can leverage to generate the static website. The layout below follows my master</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SAS</title>
      <link>/2021/03/21/sql-sas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2021/03/21/sql-sas/</guid>
      <description>SQLYou are given two non-empty linked lists representing two non-negative integers.
The digits are stored in reverse order, and each of their nodes contains a single digit.
Add the two numbers and return the sum as a linked list.
You may assume the two numbers do not contain any leading zero, except the number 0 itself.
source
For this problem we will begin with the sashelp.baseball data set.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SQL</title>
      <link>/2021/03/18/sql/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2021/03/18/sql/</guid>
      <description>DEFINATION OF RELATION TABLESHOW TO CHANGE THE ENTITY TO A SCHEMASCASE WHENSUBQUERYCOMMON TABLE EXPRESS (cte)WINDOW FUNROLLUP and CUBETABLESAMPLEUNPIVOT:ROW TO COLUMNPIVOT:COLUME TO ROWSome information contains from Datacamp, you can use my refer to get started and learn new technique together.
DEFINATION OF RELATION TABLESentity: (table) the object store the information
attribute: column in a table to describe the part of the information</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello R Markdown</title>
      <link>/2020/12/01/hello-r-markdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/12/01/hello-r-markdown/</guid>
      <description>R MarkdownThis is an R Markdown document. Markdown is a simple formatting syntax for authoring HTML, PDF, and MS Word documents. For more details on using R Markdown see http://rmarkdown.rstudio.com.
You can embed an R code chunk like this:
summary(cars)## speed dist ## Min. : 4.0 Min. : 2.00 ## 1st Qu.:12.0 1st Qu.: 26.00 ## Median :15.0 Median : 36.00 ## Mean :15.4 Mean : 42.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Plain Markdown Post</title>
      <link>/2016/12/30/a-plain-markdown-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2016 21:49:57 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/12/30/a-plain-markdown-post/</guid>
      <description>This is a post written in plain Markdown (*.md) instead of R Markdown (*.Rmd). The major differences are:
 You cannot run any R code in a plain Markdown document, whereas in an R Markdown document, you can embed R code chunks (```{r}); A plain Markdown post is rendered through Blackfriday, and an R Markdown document is compiled by rmarkdown and Pandoc.  There are many differences in syntax between Blackfriday&amp;rsquo;s Markdown and Pandoc&amp;rsquo;s Markdown.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2016 21:48:51 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>A brief introduction to myself, I graduated from York University in statistics, BA in Year 2018 and completed the master of Biostatistics at University of Toronto in year 2019. After graduated, I started as an intern associate in TD bank. After 8 months, I received a full-time position as an IT support analyst and left in November 2020.
 Why I choose the biostatisics program after graduate from York University? my personal interest in reading paper on the human&amp;rsquo;s health and curiosity on the statistics behind.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
