<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>learn on A Hugo website</title>
    <link>/categories/learn/</link>
    <description>Recent content in learn on A Hugo website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/learn/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Exploratory Data Analyst (SQL)</title>
      <link>/2022/06/21/exploratory-data-analyst-sql/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2022/06/21/exploratory-data-analyst-sql/</guid>
      <description>Exploratory Data Analyst applies to the following cases:vague targets or problems to the large data set
large data set needs cleaning
Benefit of the exploratory data analyst:help find the inner pattern or relationship through the data
help to categorize the variables for the further analysis. (missing, outlier etc.)
Three type of dataNumeric dataWe would like to know the min and max, average, variance and correlation and percentile to this type of data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meta Analysis</title>
      <link>/2021/07/09/meta-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2021/07/09/meta-analysis/</guid>
      <description>ref
NOTE: most words are from the ref above, and it is a mini summary from my own perspective. Since I am truly not able to find the better word to describe.
Meta Analysis is a method used the data results from individual studies.Studies are coming from computerized Literature Search of a database such as PudMed etc.The auto search are based on the participants, interventions, comparison and study designs indicated in the contrasts of the scientific papers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Git help</title>
      <link>/2021/05/03/githelp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2021/05/03/githelp/</guid>
      <description>Git is a free and open source distributed version control system.
working directory.
staging area(index).git repository.three different objects generate from git cmd and describe in Hash:
blob: only save the content of the file instead the file name.tree: the file name.commit: the first commit also called root commit.git basicgit init: generate a file called /.git/ used ls -a to see all the hided files.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog Down</title>
      <link>/2021/03/21/blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2021/03/21/blog/</guid>
      <description>get start:hugo go:configContentFront matterTemplates_default/list.html:terms.htmlPartials/.stores the templates reused in other html pages by the {{ partial }} function.footer.htmlCustom layoutsStatic filesLastlyAddin ….get start:here we go. already started
hugo go:a tool we we can leverage to generate the static website. The layout below follows my master
configconfig.*: in the format of . toml or yaml, the file speak globally.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SQL</title>
      <link>/2021/03/18/sql/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2021/03/18/sql/</guid>
      <description>DEFINATION OF RELATION TABLESHOW TO CHANGE THE ENTITY TO A SCHEMASCASE WHENSUBQUERYCOMMON TABLE EXPRESS (cte)WINDOW FUNROLLUP and CUBETABLESAMPLEUNPIVOT:ROW TO COLUMNPIVOT:COLUME TO ROWSome information contains from Datacamp, you can use my refer to get started and learn new technique together.
DEFINATION OF RELATION TABLESentity: (table) the object store the information
attribute: column in a table to describe the part of the information</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
